原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译：草草 Kahiko  Lynn_宁  木浅   Roya   小食人魔
翻译：Giggles  辰星晓Reginamoon   校对：木浅 某羽
时间轴：念念 烟幕迟迟 Toozii
后期：斯人      总监：木浅
诉 讼 双 雄
第七季   第三集
我得说
I have to say...
这一天我等了好久了
I've been wanting this for so long.
我最疯狂的梦中也不敢想象这会成真
Never in my wildest dreams did I think it would come true.
冠名合伙人现在只剩我们了  路易
We're the only name partners now, Louis.
我那话是真心的
And I meant it when I said it.
我希望我们能分享这样的事
I want us to share things like this.
我现在的开心简直无法言表
I can't tell you how happy that makes me.
你不会要哭吧
You're not gonna cry, are you?
开玩笑吗  我上次在这里哭
Are you kidding? The last time I cried in here,
破坏了酸碱度
I messed up the pH.
患了数周的酵母菌感染
I had a yeast infection for weeks.
你不会做另一件你告诉我你在
You're not gonna do the other thing you told me
泥巴里做过的事吧
you did in the mud, are you?
哈维  我说了  那事仅此一次
Harvey, I told you, that was a one-time thing.
相信我  你可不是蜜西・蒂特乐
And believe me, you're no Missy Dietler.
蜜西・蒂特乐是谁
Who's Missy Dietler?
-他怎么来了  -什么意思
- What is he doing here? - What do you mean?
哈维和我经常一起泥浴
Harvey and I go mudding together all the time.
你还是赶紧出来
So why don't you lug yourself out of there
-把我的浴缸还给我  -这是我的浴缸
- so I can get my tub back? - This is my tub.
你还一直跟我说  男性朋友一起洗泥浴
And you always told me it was weird for male friends
很奇怪呢
to mud together.
但哈维和我可不仅仅是朋友
But Harvey and I are more than just friends.
我们是死党
We're best friends.
然后你做了什么
And then what did you do?
你以为呢  我打给了你
What do you think I did? I called you.
路易  那只是个梦
Louis, it was just a dream.
只是个梦  那是个泥噩梦
Just a dream? It was a goddamn mud-mare.
你不懂吗
Don't you get it?
哈维让他的好哥们进了我的公司
Harvey let his buddy into my firm.
现在他进了我的泥
Now he's in my mud.
接下来呢  我走进我的浴室
I mean, what's next? I walk into my bathroom
而他在冲我的牙刷拉屎吗
and I find him shitting on my toothbrush?
路易  我们谈过的
Louis, we talked about this.
如果你被这种情绪左右
If you let this overwhelm you,
你会引起你最担心的事
you're going to bring about the thing you're most afraid of.
你听到我的话了吗
Did you hear me?
他进了我的泥
He was in my mud.
我怎么可能不被这个影响
How the hell am I not supposed to let that overwhelm me?
好吧
Well...
你有没有想过
has it occurred to you
可以不去担心这个叫亚历克斯的
that instead of worrying this Alex person
会插在你和哈维之间
is going to come between you and Harvey,
而可以以此为契机
you could use this as an opportunity
交个新朋友
to make a new friend?
那是我听过的最蠢的话了
That's the dumbest thing I've ever heard.
尽管如此
Be that as it may,
在我看来
as I see it,
你有机会多交一个朋友
you have a chance to have one more friend
也可能失去一个朋友
or one less friend.
我建议你选择朋友数量增长的
I suggest you go with one more.
-唐娜  -瑞秋
- Donna. - Rachel.
你们需要点什么吗
Can I get you two anything?
咖啡  茶  《星期日时报》上关于你的文章
Coffee, tea, a copy of your article in the "Sunday Times"?
不需要  昨天就看了  家里也有一份
Don't need it. Read it yesterday. Have one at home.
其实是十份
And by one, he means ten.
确定不想再看一遍吗
Are you sure you don't want to take just one more look at it?
不用了  谢谢  唐娜
I'm good. Thanks, Donna.
那好吧
Okeydokey.
祝你们愉快
You have a nice day.
她不太对劲  我看得出
Something's going on with her, I can tell.
什么意思
What do you mean?
你没注意到她在坏笑吗
You telling me you didn't notice that grin on her face?
瑞秋  你是比我认识唐娜更久
Rachel, you've known Donna longer than I have,
但我没看出她在坏笑
but I didn't see a grin.
我说了  我觉得是你想多了
I'm telling you, I think you're imagining it.
嗯  完全是想多了
Right. Totally imagined it.
-哈维  -瑞秋
- Harvey. - Rachel.
黑色显瘦
You know, black can be slimming.
下次要考虑到
Something to think about next time.
我想这是你在道歉
I take it this is your way of apologizing
说什么就不该再雇我回来
for saying you never should've hired me back.
也借机告诉你显瘦的问题
And it gave me a chance to say the slimming thing.
抱歉  迈克
Sorry, Mike.
你说得对  哈维
You had a point, Harvey.
这是光芒科技的合并案
This is the Radiant Technologies merger.
没错  该办我的案子了
Yep. Back to one for me.
好  但这事你不需要我
Great, except you don't need me for this.
已经完成了  明天就签了
Deal's done. They sign tomorrow.
所以克莱恩・罗宾森才以为
Which is why Klein Robinson thought that I wouldn't mind
我不介意他们临时改动一下合同
if they put a few last-minute changes in the contract.
临时改动  等于说在
And a few last-minute changes means they're trying to
最后搞鬼
pull some last-minute bullshit.
这听起来很像那个文章里报道
Now that sounds like the impressive young lawyer
厉害的年轻律师会说的话
I read about in the article.
你去查查他们在搞什么
Why don't you figure out what they're trying to do?
午饭之前搞定
And get it done by lunch.
谁说我需要显瘦
Who says I need slimming?
*看到钱  就愿意留下吃饭*
*See the money, wanna stay for your meal*
*给你太太再拿块馅饼*
*Get another piece of pie for your wife*
*所有人都想知道那感觉*
*Everybody wanna know how it feel*
*所有人都想见见那景象*
*Everybody wanna see what it's like*
*豆子馅饼我也愿吃  我不在乎*
*I'll even eat a bean pie, I don't mind*
*我和妹子忙着赚钱*
*Me and Missy is so busy, busy making money*
*好了*
*All right*
*退开点  我要跳舞*
*All step back, I'm 'bout to dance*
*美钞爵士摇摇摇*
*The greenback boogie*
诉讼双雄  第七季第三集
别敌意
Don't be hostile.
路易  你在干什么
Louis, what are you doing?
-什么  -别去烦他
- What? - Leave him alone.
他第一天上班
It's his first day.
不  唐娜  不是那样  我没有敌意
No, Donna, it's not like that. I come in peace.
你发誓
You swear?
是啊  我给他买了活物
Yes, I brought him a living thing.
-有毒吗  -不  唐娜  没有
- Is it poisonous? - No, Donna, it is not.
好吧  我盯着你呢
Okay. Well, I got my eyes on you.
还有那植物
And that plant.
别敌意
Don't be hostile.
亚历克斯・威廉姆斯  我是路易・利特
Alex Williams, Louis Litt.
我给你带了盆金银花
I brought you a honeysuckle.
什么
Excuse me?
是个好意  因为我们初识时
It's a gesture, since we might've gotten off
可能闹得不愉快
on the wrong foot.
你是指你企图偷走我最大的客户
You mean because you tried to poach my biggest client
还想阻止我加入公司
and keep me from joining the firm?
对  好像就是我们闹的那个不愉快
Yes, perhaps that's the foot we got off on.
但我希望  我们可以弄得愉快一些
But I was hoping we could get onto other foot.
给
Here.
多谢好意  路易
I appreciate the gesture, Louis.
对了
By the way,
你在安德森案上的表现太厉害了
your work on the Andersen case was extraordinary.
你关注了我的安德森案
You followed my Andersen work?
是啊  这让我想到了我的普莱豪斯策略
Yes. In fact, it reminded me of my Pricehouse strategy.
老实说  我就是根据普莱豪斯策略来的
Truth be told, I based it on your Pricehouse strategy.
不是吧  那你是更上一层楼了
Get the f--well then, you took it to a whole other level.
谢谢  路易
Thank you, Louis.
抱歉我偷你客户
I'm sorry about the poaching.
没事了
Don't worry about it.
你想一起吃午饭吗
Hey, would you like to grab lunch?
可不该用在办公室吃午饭庆祝第一天上班
Eating at your desk is no way to celebrate your first day.
没错  确实不该
You're right, it's not.
我们一点大厅见
I'll meet you at the lobby at 1:00.
挺好  谢谢你的植物
Sounds good. And thanks for the plant.
不客气
You're welcome.
不知道你在意不在意  猫很喜欢它的
I don't know if you care about this, but cats love it.
我知道  我家有两只斑猫
Oh, I know. We've got two tabbies at home
特别爱这小东西
that are gonna go crazy over that bad boy.
-斑猫  -是的
- Tabbies? - Yup.
天哪  我要去订
Holy shit, I'm gonna make a reservation
市里最棒的餐厅  一辈子的好朋友
at the best restaurant in the city, you... BFF, you.
简直服了
Son of a bitch.
雷耶斯先生吗
Mr. Reyes?
-是我  -迈克・罗斯
- Yes. - Mike Ross.
他们说你找我
They said you wanted to see me?
是的  谢谢你抽空见我
Yes, thank you for taking the time.
不必客气
Of course.
我读了关于你的报道
I read your interview yesterday.
而且我儿子也进过监狱
And my son was in prison too.
但和你不同的是
But unlike you,
他没能坚持到出狱
he didn't make it out.
上面说你儿子死于心脏病
This says your son died of a heart attack.
对  没来由的心脏病
Yes, a heart attack out of nowhere.
你觉得他们在隐瞒什么吗
You think they're hiding something.
他们不肯接我电话
Well, they won't take my calls
也不回信
or answer my letters.
如果是你你怎么想
What would you think?
我觉得可能事有蹊跷
I'd think that there might be something wrong.
但也不代表就真的有
But that doesn't mean that there is.
罗斯先生  我儿子不过28岁
Mr. Ross, my son was 28 years old.
而且他再等1个月就假释了
And he was up for parole next month.
他们一定隐瞒了我什么
There's something they're not telling me.
好  我去查查看
All right, I'll look into it.
但是我没办法短期内就开始着手
Um, but I'm not gonna be able to get to this for a few days.
短期内  为何不能现在就开始调查
A few days. Why can't you start now?
因为我和事务所有约定  事务所愿意让我
Because I have a deal with my firm that allows me
接类似这样的案子  但我还要做其他案子
to do cases like this, but not only cases like this.
而现在  我手上就有其他案子
And right now, I'm in the middle of something else.
罗斯先生  上一个我接触的律师告诉我
Mr. Ross, the last lawyer I talked to
说有个什么条例规定
said there was some kind of a statute
说我在两周之内必须提起诉讼
that says I only have another two weeks to file a lawsuit.
那我告诉你
And I'm telling you,
两周时间绰绰有余
two weeks should be more than enough time,
但我  不能为你的案子把其他事都放下
but I--I can't drop everything just to take your case.
我理解
I understand.
但是...
But...
克里斯只因为携带了1盎司大麻就进了监狱
Chris was caught with an ounce of marijuana.
他本来就不该进去的
He never should have been there in the first place.
但如果我因为时间
And if time runs out on this
不能为他伸张正义...
and I couldn't get him justice...
好
Okay.
我尽力而为
I'll see what I can do.
斯蒂芬妮  我们得谈谈这个任务
Stephanie, we need to talk about this assignment.
有什么问题吗
Is there a problem with it?
有  问题就是完成任务的不是你
Yes, the problem is you didn't do it.
是杰森
Jason did.
因为比起我  杰森更擅长编目过程
Because Jason is better at cataloging procedure than I am.
确实  但是如果你不练的话
Right, but if you don't do the things you're not good at,
你永远不会擅长
you'll never get better.
事实是  我其实也不是很想
The thing is, I don't really want to get better
擅长编目过程
at cataloging procedure.
我懂你的感受  就像我也并不是想当
I know that, just like I didn't want to be a paralegal
这么久的专事调查的法务助理
specializing in research for as long as I was.
但去年我们赢了一个案子
But it turns out we had a case last year
恰恰赢在我擅长调查
that we only won because I was outstanding at research.
好  我了解了
Okay, I see your point.
-我不会再这样了  -好
- I won't do it again. - Good.
因为我有另一个案子
Because I have another case that requires some procedure
也需要编目过程  我专门留给了你
to be catalogued, and I put it aside especially for you.
但斯蒂芬妮  我希望你能保证
But Stephanie, I want your word
你不会再推给杰森
that you won't pawn it off on Jason.
我向你保证
You have my word.
看看谁打过来了
Well, look who it is.
别告诉我你上次爽约很后悔
Don't tell me, you feel bad about canceling the other night
现在迫不及待得想补偿我
and now you're dying to make it up to me.
简直就像你会读心术
It's as though you read my mind.
这是我众多技能之一好吧
One of my many skills.
今晚一起吃晚餐怎么样
How does dinner tonight sound?
那不如就来我家吃
How does having it at my place sound?
狡猾如你哦
You're a crafty one, aren't you?
怎么  只是因为我
What? I've got some steaks
存了些牛排  一直想处理掉
I've been wanting to throw on the grill.
才不是  你想在你家吃是因为
No, you want to have dinner at your place
它是城区里离你卧室最近的
'cause it's the closest restaurant in the city
餐厅
to your bedroom.
你在大众点评查到的吗
Did you read that in "Zagat's"?
不  因为读了你的心
No, I read your mind.
那你知道我希望几点见面吗
Then what time am I thinking?
8点好不好
How about 8:00?
8点半吧  我还得去买牛排
Better make it 8:30. I got to go buy some steaks.
正想找你呢
Good, you're here.
快告诉我你搞清楚
Tell me you figured out what bullshit
他们想在这个案子里搞什么鬼了
they're trying to sneak into this deal.
他们不是想在案子里搞鬼
They're not trying to sneak anything into it.
他们是想尽快结掉案子
They're trying to get out of it.
没道理啊
That doesn't make sense.
他们是因为这个并购找我们的
They came to us for this merger.
那他们现在一定是有更好的报价了
They must've gotten a better offer,
因为他们在补遗里隐藏了
because they buried an escape clause
免除条款
in the addendum.
-你知道我们得干什么  -我知道
- You know what we have to do. - Yes, I do.
但你得自己做了
But you're gonna have to do it without me.
我有其他要事要做  时间很紧的那种
Something's come up, it's on a deadline,
而且我需要把它做好
and I need to take care of it.
-什么样的事情  -一个法律援助
- What kind of thing? - A pro bono thing.
什么时候成了给我一个给你两个了
Since when does one for me mean two for you?
哈维  一个囚犯死在监狱  事有蹊跷
Harvey, a man died in prison and it doesn't smell right.
而且我得知此事的唯一原因
Also, the only reason I found out about it is
是我接受你的意见  做了采访
I took your advice and did that interview.
所以你不帮我做案子还是我的不是了
So it's my fault that you're dropping my case?
对  你能这么想挺好的
Yeah, I like to look at it that way.
认真的  把案子办漂亮
Seriously, go get 'em.
谢了  哈维
Thanks, Harvey.
上个来看我的人送的是花
The last guy brought me a plant.
让我猜猜  是路易
Let me guess, the last guy was Louis.
-你猜对了  -我向你保证
- You got it. - Well, I guarantee
我的欢迎礼物一定比他的更值得期待
my welcome gift is a lot more fun than his.
现在连合并都值得期待了吗
Since when is a merger signing fun?
因为合并方打算把我们生吞活剥
Since the guys on the other side are trying to rip us off
还以为我们不知道
and think we don't know.
你之前怎么不告诉我呢
Why didn't you tell me that in the first place?
好啦  我路上告诉你
Come on. I'll fill you in on the way over.
等下  会议这么快开始吗
Wait, the meeting's now?
是啊  有什么问题吗
Yeah, is that a problem?
我和路易约了午餐
I told Louis we'd get lunch.
生意比午餐重要  他会体谅的
Business trumps lunch. Louis'll understand.
给他打个电话告知一下就行了
Just call him and let him know.
艾利克斯  你好  我正要去见你
Alex, hi, I was just on my way to meet you.
关于这事  路易  我只能改约了
About that, Louis. I have to reschedule.
工作上出了事  希望你能谅解
A work thing came up. I hope you understand.
没问题
Yeah, of course.
-生意重要  -谢谢体谅
-  Business comes first. - Thanks.
我们下次再约  事实上我这周都可以
We'll do it another time. In fact, I'm free all week.
路易  你还好吧
Louis? You okay?
在  我没事
Uh, yeah, I'm okay.
我  那个  过敏高发季
I, uh-- it's allergy season.
我在想可能今天还是不一起吃饭比较好
I--I think it's probably best that we don't have lunch today.
我...我感觉胸闷气短
I, uh--my--my chest feels like a vice.
没事吧
All good?
应该没事
I think so.
不过他送了你什么植物
What kind of plant did he get you, anyway?
金银花
Honeysuckle.
我从来不知道金银花还能家养
I never knew that was an indoor plant.
可以家养的
Can be.
事实上  我家的猫会很喜欢的
Matter of fact, our cats are gonna love it.
-你还养猫  -你这表情什么意思
- You have cats? - Why you gotta be like that?
-你为什么要养猫  -我喜欢猫
- Why you gotta have cats? - I like my cats.
你才不喜欢
No, you don't.
施耐德女士  我是迈克・罗斯
Ms. Snyder? Mike Ross.
我应该听说过这个名字吗
Is that name supposed to mean something to me?
不  但我是克里斯・雷耶斯家人的律师
No, but I'm representing the family of Chris Reyes.
希望你熟悉这个名字
Hoping that name does.
当然
Of course.
我们对每个
Any time an inmate dies,
死去的囚犯都十分负责
we take it very seriously.
但却不足以负责到向他频繁询问
But not seriously enough to give an accounting of his death
死因的家属一个合理解释
despite repeated requests by his family.
我没有收到他家属的质询
I received no such requests.
你没有先来电通知拜访太可惜了
It's a shame you didn't call first.
我本来可以准备些什么的
I could've prepared something.
就是想杀你个措手不及
I didn't want you to be prepared,
因为我知道事有隐情
'cause I want to know what actually happened.
罗斯先生  当你坐了我的位子
Mr. Ross, when you do what I do,
就会对人们总认为你公司做坏事习以为常
you get used to people assuming the worst about your company,
所以希望你能稍微尊重我一点
so I would appreciate a little respect.
施耐德女士  当你坐了我的位子
Ms. Snyder, when you do what I do,
你就会习惯那些公司总是如你所料
you get used to companies proving you right,
所以我希望你们能有所行动
so I would appreciate a little action.
看来是雷耶斯先生和其他犯人打架
Apparently Mr. Reyes was in a fight.
他被关了禁闭
He was sent to solitary,
期间他声称自己呼吸困难
where he complained of difficulty breathing.
监狱传唤了一位医生为他治疗
A doctor was called and delivered treatment.
不幸的是  他于几小时后身亡了
Unfortunately, he died a few hours later.
如果他和犯人打架
Well, if he was in a fight,
那就一定有事故报告
there has to be an incident report.
也许  但你无权查阅
That may be, but you have no right to access it.
我们是私营公司  有这个特权
We're a private corporation. That's privileged.
好  那把目睹此事的警卫名字告诉我
Okay, then how about you give me the names of the guards who saw it?
你知道我是不能告诉你的
You know I can't give you that either.
你也知道  我如果起诉你们
And you know that if I bring a suit against you,
一样还是能获得这些信息
I'm gonna get all of this anyway.
所以你何不省省这曝光度
So why don't you save yourself the publicity
直接把信息给我
and just give it to me now?
我不在乎那上面是怎么写的
I don't care what that thing says.
这不是事情的全部
It's not the whole story.
雷耶斯先生  我知道这不是你想要的
Mr. Reyes, I know this isn't what you wanted to hear,
但我不认为有案可诉
but I'm not seeing a case.
上面说我儿子是在单独禁闭室死的
It says there that my son died alone in solitary confinement.
他们为什么不把他送到医务室
Why didn't they take him to an infirmary?
因为有医生来给他治疗了
Because he was seen by a doctor.
关于他的症状是有解释的
There was an explanation for his symptoms.
我知道你觉得我只是不能接受自己孩子的死亡
I know you think I'm just a man who can't accept his child's death.
但不是这样的
But that's not true.
雷耶斯先生  在监狱打架确实可能让人心率上升
Mr. Reyes, a fight in prison can elevate your heart rate.
我对这一点最清楚不过的了
Nobody knows that better than I do.
他们给的理由说得通
What they're saying happened is plausible.
那是因为你不了解我儿子
Then you didn't know my son.
我告诉过你  他下个月就能假释出狱
I told you, he was up for parole next month.
他根本就不会和别人打架
He wouldn't have gotten into a fight.
你到底想说什么
What exactly are you saying?
一定是有犯人故意去找他麻烦
One of those inmates must have come for him.
而监狱不在乎克里斯
And that prison didn't give enough of a shit about Chris
没能保护他
to protect him.
雷耶斯先生  我知道你来找我
Mr. Reyes, I know that you came to me
是因为那篇文章上说我希望能帮助百姓
because that article said I wanted to help people
我也确实希望  但是...
and I do, but...
我知道  我儿子已经死了
I know. My son's already dead.
但假如他们本能阻止这种事  却听之任之
But if they could've stopped this and they didn't,
那以后还会有类似情况
it's going to happen again.
蔡斯  这位是我们最新一位高级合伙人
Chase, I'd like you to meet our newest senior partner,
亚历克斯・威廉姆斯
Alex Williams.
签个合同居然劳两位高级合伙人大驾
Two senior partners just to sign a contract.
有点太隆重了吧
Seems excessive.
的确  但我们不是来签合同的
It would be, but we're not here to sign anything.
什么意思
What are you talking about?
他一定觉得我挺傻的
He must think I'm pretty dumb.
人们总是低估长得好看的人
People always underestimate a pretty face.
也许他只是觉得你傻而已
Maybe he just thinks you're dumb.
因为你那下耷的眼角
'Cause of the droopy eyes.
有道理  并非没有这个先例
Valid theory. Not unprecedented.
没人觉得你们傻
Nobody thinks you're dumb.
那你为什么把这个条款
Then why the hell did you sneak this clause
偷偷地加进了我的合同里
to the back of my goddamn contract?
我们没有偷偷加什么
We didn't sneak anything.
我们只是想看看还有没有其他选择
We were just looking at our options.
放屁  你是想用我们当幌子
Bullshit. You're trying to use us as a stalking horse
这样你就可以和哥本合并了
so you can merge with Gorban.
是又如何
So what if I was?
你们准备怎么阻止我
What are you going to do to stop it?
告诉你我是怎么做的  我找了亚历克斯
I'll tell you what I did. I called Alex.
而我找了我在司法部工作的法学院室友
And what I did was call my law school roommate at the DOJ
聊了聊你和哥本合并可能造成的垄断
about the anti-trust issues raised by you merging with Gorban.
你们想怎么样
What do you want?
我们希望你能遵守原合同的条约
We want you to live up to the terms of the original agreement.
除了一条
With one exception.
你得辞职
You're gonna take a step down.
-我是不会辞职的  -不  你会
- I'm not stepping down. - Yes, you are.
这家新公司不需要两个外聘律师
This new company doesn't need two outside counsels.
尤其不需要一位背着客户
Particularly one who tries to pull shady shit
搞小动作的律师
without his client knowing about it.
看来你得为了团队牺牲自己了  蔡斯
Looks like you're gonna take one for the team, Chase.
问题是  你是想体面地退场还是被踢出去
The question is, would you like to bow out or get kicked out?
我他妈怎么能平静得下来
How the hell can I calm down?
我眼睁睁地看着我的泥浴噩梦成真了
I was watching my mud-mare come true.
你不清楚你到底看到了什么  路易
You don't know what you saw, Louis.
抱歉  我不记得我瞎了
I'm sorry, I forgot I was blind.
我一定是用盲人手机打给你的
I must've dialed your number using my Braille-a-phone.
你知道我不是这个意思
You know that's not what I meant.
不  你是对的  这是唯一能解释
No, you're right, it's the only explanation
我为什么会不清楚我看到的东西
as to why I wouldn't know what I just saw,
也就是哈维和亚历克斯  手挽着手嘲笑我
which was Harvey and Alex, arm in arm, laughing at me!
路易  听我说
Louis, listen to me.
我们早知道会发生这样的事
We knew this was going to happen.
我会被我最好的朋友背叛这件事吗
That I was gonna be betrayed by my best friend?
不  是你想要努力对别人友好...
No, that you were going to try to be good--
-做过了  -试着不做你自己
- Did it. - Try not to be you.
-做到了  -然后以为发生了
- Accomplished. - Then perceive
一个可能并不存在的侮慢
a potentially nonexistent slight
直接就跳到了第七阶段
and go straight to stage seven.
你到底在说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
惊恐  悲伤  自我厌恶
Panic, sorrow, self-loathing,
憎恨  辩解  再次自我厌恶  愤怒
hatred, justification, self-loathing again, and rage.
我把这叫做路易的七个阶段
I call it the seven stages of Louis.
你胡说八道
You are so full of shit,
你真是个大骗子  我会...
and you're a total fraud, and I'm actually gonna--
我懂你的意思了
I see your point.
7b阶段
Stage 7b.
没有人喜欢幸灾乐祸的人  斯坦
No one likes a gloater, Stan.
尽管如此
Be that as it may.
你需要制定个策略  路易
You need a strategy, Louis.
为了现在和下次再发生这种情况的时候
For now and the next time this happens.
呼吸练习
The breathing exercises.
那是对你有用的唯一办法
It's the only thing that's ever worked for you.
没有你我可怎么办  医生
What would I do without you, Doc?
不必想这个问题  我的朋友
No need to go down that road, my friend.
现在  想象你自己在靠近海的地方
Now, picture yourself near the ocean,
躺在沙子上
laying in the sand.
很好  不是吗
Isn't it lovely?
我得说  那很有趣
I got to say, that was pretty fun.
我也觉得
I agree.
我一直想假装我有个在司法部的朋友
I always wanted to pretend I had a friend at the DOJ.
第一天过得挺不错的
Not a bad first day.
说到我的第一天
Speaking of my first day,
路易・利特那个家伙是怎么回事
what's up with that Louis Litt guy?
-什么意思  -我不知道
- What do you mean? - I don't know.
一开始他试图阻止我来
First he tries to stop me from coming over,
之后他带给我一盆植物
then he brings me a plant,
再然后当我打电话取消午饭安排的时候
then when I called to cancel lunch,
我敢发誓他简直要哭出来了
I could've sworn he was about to cry or something.
什么
What?
路易这个人...
Louis is...
一言难尽
he's complicated.
什么意思  一言难尽
What do you mean, complicated?
你知道他不想让你来这  对吗
Well, you know he didn't want you here, right?
问题是  并不是出于工作原因
The thing is, it wasn't professional.
那还能是什么
What else could it be?
他怕我会和你
He was worried that I was gonna be
成为比他更要好的朋友
better friends with you than him.
这家伙什么毛病啊
What the hell is wrong with this guy?
他喜欢上了你吗
Does he have a crush on you?
不
No.
是  他完全迷上我了
Yeah, he totally has a crush on me.
但不是那种喜欢
But not like that.
也许这么解释你就明白了
Maybe this'll work.
你看过《陆军野战医院》吗
You ever seen "MASH"?
当然看过  但和这又有什么关系
Of course, but what does that have to do with this?
路易是弗兰克・勃恩斯
Louis is Frank Burns.
你怎么不早说
Why didn't you say so in the first place?
这下我就理解了
Now I totally get it.
-你确定  -是的
- You sure? - Yeah.
他爱你  恨你  想要成为你
He loves you, hates you, and wants to be you,
三种感情同时存在
all at the same time.
你的确理解了
Huh, you do get it.
是的  问题是
Yeah, I do. The question is,
你确定我俩会没事
are you sure he's gonna be okay with me,
还是我得小心点
or do I have to watch out?
我问你
Well, let me ask you this.
你告诉他你的猫会喜欢他的金银花了吗
Did you tell him your cats are gonna love his honeysuckle?
说了
Yes.
那我想你肯定没事
Then I think you'll be fine.
打扰一下  你们认识克里斯・雷耶斯吗
Excuse me. You guys know Chris Reyes?
没听过
Doesn't ring a bell.
那就奇怪了  因为根据事故报告
That's strange, 'cause according to the incident report
他死的当晚是你们三个值班
the three of you were on duty the night he died.
就算真是如此  我也没什么好说的
Even if I were, I wouldn't have anything to say about it,
所以你可以滚了
so you can get the fu-- out of here.
别这样  我只想问几个问题  别无其他
Hey, come on. I just have a few questions, that's all.
这里是监狱
This is a prison.
所有的问题都得通过总办公室
All questions go through the main office.
你觉得我从哪搞到你们的名字的
Where do you think I got your names?
我一点都不关心你从哪搞到的
I don't give a shit where you got 'em.
你得忘了你听过这几个名字
You're gonna forget you ever heard 'em.
再让我见到你  我让你吃不了兜着走
And if I see your face again, there's gonna be a problem.
好了  我不是来这找麻烦的
Okay, look, I'm not trying to start any trouble here.
但死了人  我得弄清楚发生了什么
But a man is dead, and I need to find out what happened.
对于一个不是来找麻烦的人来说
For a guy who's not looking to cause any trouble,
你没有做到认真听别人的话
you sure don't listen too good.
好了  德鲁  走吧
Come on, Drew. Let's go.
那正是他想要的
That's what he wants.
我告诉你  他不值得
I'm telling you, he's not worth it.
你就是那种喜欢
You're one of those assholes who just love
被打得屁滚尿流的那种人是吗
getting the shit beat out of him, aren't you?
不  我被打得屁滚尿流过
No, I've had the shit beat out of me,
我可以告诉你  我一点也不喜欢那样
and I can tell you, I didn't love it at all.
那你最好快点滚出去
Then you better get the hell out of here
免得旧事重演
before it happens again.
我会的  只要你回答我的问题
I will, just as soon as you answer my questions.
我为什么要回答
And why would I do that?
因为你的名字列于名单之首
Because your name is at the top of the list,
我想你知道那意味着什么
and I'm guessing you know what that means.
是啊  我是替罪羊
Yeah, I'm the scapegoat.
但也意味着无论他们知道了什么
But it also means anything they get,
他们都知道是从我这里泄露的
they know it came from me.
不过你刚当着你同事的面
Except you just told me to go to hell
让我滚远点
in front of all your buddies,
他们看的出你是认真的
and they saw you meant it.
所以你才到监狱找我
That's why you came to me at the prison.
现在你有掩护了
Now you got cover.
我建议你好好利用
And I suggest you use it.
因为我一定会弄清楚到底发生了什么
Because I am gonna find out what happened here,
到那时  他们会为自保推卸责任
and when I do, they are gonna shield themselves from liability
那我只能追着你不放
and I am gonna end up coming after you instead.
或者你告诉我我所需要的知道的
Or you can tell me what I need to know,
我就不把你卷进来
and I'll leave you out of it.
是我分开了打架的人
I'm the one who pulled him out of the fight
把他关了紧闭
and threw him in the hole.
他开始说他呼吸有问题
He started complaining saying he was having problems breathing.
我告诉了我的主管
I told my supervisor,
我的主管说他会叫医生来的
and my supervisor said he was gonna call the doctor.
-我就知道这么多  -鬼才信你只知道这么多
- That's all I know. - Bullshit that's all you know.
克里斯被杀是因为他知道了不该知道的事吗
Look, did Chris get killed because he was onto something?
-不  -那孩子
- No. - Well, that kid,
他不会毫无理由就卷进打架事件
he didn't just up and get in a fight without good reason.
你不知道你在说什么
You don't know what you're talking about.
看守受贿了吗
Look, are the guards corrupt?
你刚刚说什么
What the hell did you just say?
-是外面的什么人要教训他吗  -不  他只是死了
- Was somebody out to get him? - No, he just died!
没有什么阴谋诡计
Look, there's no conspiracy.
没有坏人
Nobody's evil.
只是廉价
Just cheap.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
他们能揍他那么久的
It means the only reason they were able to wale on him
唯一原因
for as long as they did
是因为那晚值班人员不够
is 'cause they didn't have enough of us on duty that night,
因为监狱除了自己的收益
'cause the prison doesn't give a shit about anything
其他都不关心
except its bottom line.
那你怎么做的
So what did you do?
然后我告诉他钱可以收下
So I told him he could have the money,
但要是想拿走这些唱片
but if--if he tried taking those albums,
我俩就有麻烦了
we're gonna have trouble.
今晚真美好
This was lovely.
但我明天得早起
But I have an early morning tomorrow.
我觉得我该回家了
I think I should get home.
宝拉  怎么回事
Paula, what's going on?
没事
It's nothing.
-真的  -没事吗
- Really. - Nothing?
我们度过了美好的一
We had a great night.
突然你就说要走
All of a sudden you have to go?
你不会明白的
You wouldn't understand.
说说看
Try me.
今天我和我以前的女导师共进午餐
I had lunch with the woman who was my mentor today.
我们吃得很开心
And we were having a wonderful time
闲聊叙旧
catching up with each other,
然后...  突然
and then... out of the blue,
她问我是否有交往的人
she asked me if I was seeing anyone.
我说没有
I said no.
我们交往时间还不算长
Well, we haven't exactly been seeing each other for very long.
我可以理解如果你...
It's understandable if you--
不是这样的  哈维
No, it wasn't that, Harvey.
-而是我感觉有点... -什么
- It's that I felt a little... - What?
羞愧
ashamed.
Ashamed.
我俩之间的关系不是闹着玩  哈维
This isn't a small thing, what we're doing, Harvey.
-至少对我来说不是  -对我来说也不是
- At least it's not to me. - It's not to me either.
我不确定自己清楚这事有多认真
Well, I'm not sure I realized exactly how not small it is
直到今天
until today.
我不明白  这事我们讨论过了
I don't understand. We've been over this.
规定说得很清楚
It's in writing.
我们交往并不违规
There's no violation with us seeing each other.
我不是想要逃避什么惩罚  哈维
This isn't something that I am trying to get away with, Harvey.
而是关于我内心的感受
It's how I'm feeling inside.
-所以你想说什么  -我什么都没说
- So what are you saying? - I'm not saying anything.
我只是说  我觉得自己今晚该回家过夜
I'm just saying I think I should sleep at my place tonight.
唐娜  我有话要对你说
Donna, I need to talk to you about something.
说什么
About what?
告诉你我很生气
About the fact that I'm pissed off.
怎么回事
What's going on?
我交给斯蒂芬妮・帕特尔一个任务
I gave Stephanie Patel an assignment
然后她把任务交给了别人
and she handed it off.
你跟她谈过了吗
Did you talk to her about it?
谈过了  她向我保证
Yes, I did, and she gave me her word
下不为例  但她又这样做了
that she would never do it again, but she did.
我不明白  这上面有斯蒂芬妮的名字
I don't understand. This has Stephanie's name on it.
我不管上面写着谁的名字
I don't care whose name is on it.
都必须由初级助理
There's no way that that wasn't written
亲自完成
by a first-year associate.
瑞秋  别告诉我你想
Rachel, please tell me you're not thinking
拿着这个去找路易
about going to Louis with this.
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
就因为路易和斯蒂芬妮之间的小插曲
We took Louis off the associates
我们才让他放手了新律师
because of his incident with Stephanie.
如果我告诉路易她违抗命令
If I tell him that she's being insubordinate,
路易会杀了她的
he'll kill her.
不敢相信我会说这个
Well, I can't believe I'm saying this,
但也许你该向路易学一招
but maybe you should take a page out of Louis' book.
这是什么意思
What do you mean?
路易刚接管新律师的时候
When Louis first took over the associates,
他常常会安排一个假律师
he used to plant a fake associate
然后在上班第一天  当众炒了他
and fire him in front of the entire class on day one.
我过去认为他真是疯了
And I used to think he was crazy,
但斯蒂芬妮从未
but Stephanie never would have pulled
跟路易来这一套
something like this with Louis.
好吧  首先
Okay, first of all,
这无关我的管理方式
that's just not how I operate.
其次  路易那招他们都见过了
And second of all, they've all been here.
都能看出那是演戏
They'd all be able to tell that it was fake.
那也许你应该真的解雇她
Then maybe you need to real fire her.
因为这是她再犯了  如果你继续放任自流
Because this is a second offense and if you keep letting it go,
何时才是个头
where does it end?
我不会这么做
I'm not gonna do that.
介意我问问原因吗
Do you mind if I ask you why not?
因为我不想刚上任就踢人走
Because I don't want my first official act to be firing someone.
我理解  瑞秋
I understand that, Rachel.
但你最好想点别的办法
But you better think of something.
因为路易一直都很明白
Because the one thing that Louis understood
不是你说一不二
was that you've got to come out of the gate in command,
就是他们骑到你脖子上
or they're gonna walk all over you.
你好
Yes?
雷耶斯先生  我是迈克・罗斯
Mr. Reyes, it's Mike Ross.
我去了监狱  和一个狱警谈了谈
I went to the prison, and I talked to one of the guards.
他怎么说
What did he say?
他说所有监狱都只在乎自己的收益
He said all the prison cares about is their bottom line.
所以我今晚会发起诉讼
So I'm filing a lawsuit tonight.
太谢谢你了  罗斯先生
Thank you so much, Mr. Ross.
我本以为那个故事不太现实
I thought that article was maybe too good to be true.
谢谢你这么说  奥斯卡
I appreciate that, Oscar,
但在我最终如你所愿之前  先别谢谢我
but don't thank me until I get you the answers you're looking for.
你已经把文件都做好了吗
You finished the paperwork already?
看来得给你升职加薪了
I might have to give you a raise.
把钱省省吧  哈维
Save your money, Harvey.
我来是想说点别的
I'm here about something else.
怎么了
What's going on?
我刚听说迈克・罗斯在处理一个无偿服务案
I just heard Mike Ross is handling a pro bono.
是的  我跟他有个协议
Yeah, we have a deal.
怎么了  你想让他做什么吗
Why? You need him for something?
是的  我想让他放弃这个案子
Yeah, I need him to drop that case.
为什么
Why?
因为这和马斯特森建筑公司有利益冲突
Because there's a conflict with Masterson Construction.
迈克的无偿服务案是针对一个监狱
Mike's pro bono is against some prison.
你猜是谁建的这些监狱
And guess who builds those prisons.
等等
Wait a second.
你是在说  因为你客户在欺压你
Are you telling me to go back on my word
所以让我出尔反尔吗
because your client's bullying you?
哈维  我以为我们是一条船上的
Harvey, I thought we were in this together.
-同意  -那就听我的
- So did I. - Then get on board.
因为他们不是普通客户
Because they're not just any client.
而是我最大的客户之一
They're one of my biggest.
如果因为你把一个无名囚犯放在一个
And if they leave because you chose some prisoner
全国大型开发商之前  导致他们离开
over one of the biggest developers in the country,
外界就会从中得到消息
people are gonna get the message
认为我们无意与房地产企业合作
that we don't want to be in the real estate business.
他们说过会放出这个消息吗
Did they say they were gonna give people that message?
-哈维  -说过还是没说
- Harvey-- - Did they or not?
-说了  -放弃他们
- They did. - Drop 'em.
-我的天  -我说放弃他们
- God damn it-- - I said drop 'em.
-不  -你说什么
- No. - Excuse me?
我可能还不是冠名合伙人
I may not be name partner yet,
但我要代理什么客户不用你来告诉我
but you don't get to tell me who my clients are.
我就是要告诉你
Yes, I do.
哈维  听听你自己说的话
Harvey, listen to yourself.
这只是个无偿服务案  他刚接手
It's one pro bono. He just took it.
完全可以撤诉
He can drop it.
我向他保证过
I gave him my word.
你也曾经向我保证过
And you once gave your word to me
然后出尔反尔  而我计较
and went back on it and I let it go.
因为我懂这是生意
Because I understood it was business.
要是这小子不懂  那他在这干嘛
If this kid doesn't get that, what the hell is he doing here?
斯特芬妮  我叫你来我办公室
Stephanie, I asked you to come to my office.
已经是一个小时前的事了
That was over an hour ago.
我刚刚在写桑德森简报
I was working on the Sanderson brief.
就准备过来了
I was about to come down.
我现在就跟你说
Well, I need to talk to you now,
因为你告诉我不会把这个移交给别人
because you told me that you wouldn't hand this off,
你却这么干了
and you did.
不  我告诉你我不会把这个移交给杰森
No, I told you that I wouldn't hand it off to Jason,
我确实没有
and I didn't.
你难道是要玩文字游戏
I'm sorry, are you trying to get out of this
撇清责任吗
on a technicality?
我是你的主管  不是你的对方律师
I'm your supervisor, not opposing counsel.
瑞秋  我试过委婉一点
Rachel, I tried to be nice about this,
但我已经当了四年律师了
but I'm a fourth-year associate,
不会再浪费时间
and I'm not wasting my time
做一些菜鸟律师做的事了
on something a first-year could handle.
不介意的话  我回去工作了
Now, if you don't mind, I would like to get back to work.
我介意
Actually, I do mind.
很抱歉  斯特芬妮  我跟你说
Excuse me, Stephanie, I'm speaking to you.
你当了几年律师不重要
It doesn't matter what year you are.
我是律师主管
I'm head of the associates.
我给你任务  你就得做
If I give you an assignment, you do it.
值得我费时间做的  我会做
And when you give me one that's worth my time, I will.
这是怎么了
What's going on here?
唐娜  我来解决
Donna, I'm handling it.
作为一个成年女性
What's going on is that I am a grown woman,
我不需要别人告诉我该做什么
and I don't need to be told what to do by someone
尤其是经验没我丰富的人
with less experience as a lawyer than me.
那你可能更不想听到没有律师经验的人
Then you're really gonna hate being told what to do
告诉你该做什么了
by someone with no experience as a lawyer.
-唐娜...  -你说什么
- Donna-- - Excuse me?
既然你来了我这里
I said, you're here, and I'm here.
如果你想给我办事
So unless you want to deal with me,
你就得听瑞秋的话
you'll listen when Rachel tells you something.
我被招募到这里来
I was recruited to come here.
你们告诉我  我会受到重视
And I was told that I would be valued
因为我的智慧  我带来的收益
for my mind, my billings,
我带来的客户资源
and my relationship with my clients.
但来了这
And since I got here,
我得收拾路易的烂摊子
I have had to take shit from Louis.
你现在还要求我浪费时间精力
And now you're asking me to waste my time and my ability
在这些事情上面
on something like this.
你没错  斯特芬妮
You're right, Stephanie.
你不该因为路易被这样对待
You shouldn't have been treated like that by Louis.
瑞秋和我会处理这件事
And Rachel and I took care of it.
至于你的时间精力
Now as for your time and ability,
如果你不好好完成瑞秋交待的任务
if you don't do whatever assignment Rachel gives you,
我才不管你有多优秀
I don't give a shit how good you are.
我们会直接让你走人
We are gonna show you the door.
你过来跟我说我帮了你大忙吗
Did you come by to tell me that the work I did saved your ass?
确实帮了大忙  但我不是为这个来
It did, but that's not why I'm here.
哈维  怎么了
Harvey, what's going on?
你得放弃公益案
You have to drop your pro bono.
它跟我们一个客户有冲突
There's a conflict with one of our clients.
什么  谁啊  我接案子之前
What? Who? I checked for conflicts
核实过有没有利益冲突
before I took the case.
-一个新客户  -既然是新客户
- It's a new client. - Well, if it's a new client,
那直接跟他们解约好了
then let's drop them.
不能  他们是一家很大的开发商
We can't. They're a huge developer.
开发商啊  我在起诉一家监狱
A developer? I'm suing a prison.
我知道  但是他们说...
I know that, but they're saying--
我才不管他们说什么
I don't care what they're saying.
这不是有冲突  这是在敲诈
That's not a conflict. That's a shakedown.
-迈克  -不
- Mike-- - No.
你打算给了我通行证
You're gonna give me the green light,
我找到要的东西了
and then I find something,
你就让我无缘无故放弃吗
and then you're gonna make me dump them for no good reason?
这不是没有原因啊
It's not no good reason.
他是亚历克斯的开发商  我刚招他进来
It's Alex's developer, and I just brought him in.
第一个星期就让他失去
I let him lose one of his biggest clients
一个大客户吗  简直是噩梦
his first week here, it's a disaster.
那我不伸张正义  眼睁睁看着他死吗
And I let a man die without getting him justice.
-这算哪门子事  -听我说...
- What the hell is that? - Listen to me--
你自己想想  我们说好的
Listen to yourself. We had a deal.
这个小丑让我
Now this clown is asking me to drop a client
跟我做了承诺的客户解约
that I made a promise to.
他没让你解约  迈克
Except he's not asking you to drop him, Mike.
是我  你不答应我们说好的就不算了
I am. And if you don't, that deal we made--it's over.
你怎么能那样做
How could you do that?
怎么做  我在帮你
Do what? I was helping you.
不  唐娜  你破坏了我的权威
No, Donna, you were undermining me.
破坏你的权威
Undermining you?
你需要支援  所以我才那么做
You needed backup. That's what I'm here for.
不  我需要解决问题
No, I needed to handle the situation,
而我正在解决问题时
which is what I was doing until you decided to interfere
你不清楚状况就来搅合
in something that you don't know anything about.
无意冒犯  瑞秋  但我确实知道情况
No offense, Rachel, but I did know something about it,
据我所知  你根本没法把问题解决好
and from what I could tell, you weren't handling it at all.
那你觉得你这样做有用吗
And you think what you did was any better?
我早就告诉过你要给公司定好基调
I think I told you that you need to set the tone early on.
你刚刚定的基调就是
Okay, and the tone that you just set
你要是不在  她就可以骑到我脖子上来了
is that if you're not there, she can walk all over me.
我不知道你在哪间办公室
Well, I don't know what room you were in,
但她早就爬你头上了
but she was doing that anyway.
要是其他律师看到我放任她这么做
And what does it say about me if the other associates
他们会怎么议论我
see me letting her do that?
你说好了相信我的领导能力
What it says is that you trust my leadership style
就不应该还以为你得为我抗争
instead of thinking that you need to fight my fights for me.
斯特芬妮需要我给她的一切
Stephanie needed what I gave her.
你要是以为我是在为你抗争
And if you think that was me fighting your fights,
你都不知道你在说些什么
you don't know what you're talking about.
因为如果是针对我
Because if it were up to me,
我早就把她炒了
I would've fired her on the spot.
那你怎么不炒呢
Well then, why didn't you?
因为他们不是我的律师
Because they're not my associates.
你说的对  他们是我的律师
You're right. They're mine.
我在努力帮你争取他们
And I fought for you to get them.
你刚刚在他们所有人面前
And you just belittled me
藐视我  羞辱我
and embarrassed me in front of all of them.
我以为我的朋友
And that is not something that I thought
不会对我这么做
my friend would do to me.
我从没想过我会说下面的话
Well, you know what, I never thought I would say this,
也许你还没为你的新职位做好准备
but maybe you weren't ready for your new position.
你知道吗  唐娜
Well, you know what, Donna?
你也没有
Maybe neither were you.
利普希茨医生  我知道你还在治疗
Dr. Lipschitz, I, uh-- I know you're in a session.
我只是想说你是对的
I just wanted to say that you were right.
我反应过度了
Uh, I was overreacting.
我没有对亚历克斯不满
I do not have a problem with Alex.
如果我再有了什么情绪
And, uh, if I ever get triggered again,
我会深呼吸
I have the deep breathing.
再次感谢
Anyway, thanks again.
再见
Auf Wiedersehen.
迈克
Mike.
很高兴见到你
It's good to see you.
我只需要几分钟就够了  之后你随便用
This'll just take a few minutes, and then it's all yours.
多久并不要紧  路易
No, it doesn't matter how long it takes, Louis.
反正跟客户收到钱就行了  对吧
We can just charge the time back to some client, right?
反正这儿的人只在乎赚钱
'Cause nobody around here gives a shit about anything
其他的事一概不想管
other than making money anyway.
迈克  发生什么了
Mike, what is going on?
事情是  我回来的唯一原因
What's going on is that the only reason I came back here
是哈维和我曾经有过约定
is that Harvey and I made a deal,
然而还不到一周
and it hasn't even been a week,
他就把这忘到脑后了
and he's already going back on it.
在我监管下不会发生这种事情的  好吗
That's not gonna happen on my watch. Okay?
所以冷静一下
So just slow down.
告诉我你说的到底是怎么回事
Tell me what the hell you're talking about.
哈维  我们需要谈谈
Harvey, we need to talk.
迈克刚刚告诉我  你打破了和他的约定
Mike just told me you're breaking a deal with him.
他不该跟你说这些的
Well, he shouldn't have told you that,
因为这不关你事
because that's none of your business.
不关我事
None of my business?
我的名字就写在墙上  和你的一样
My name's on the wall as much as yours.
听着  如果迈克不放弃诉讼的话
Look, if Mike doesn't drop that case,
我们就要失去一个大客户了
we lose a major client.
-那我接受不了  -不  哈维
- I can't have that. - No, Harvey.
我们接受不了的是你开创了个先例
What we can't have is you setting a precedent
让亚历克斯的客户骑在我们头上作威作福
that Alex's clients can run roughshod all over us.
你们小点声
Keep your voices down.
我明白了
Oh, I get it.
这不是关于我打破了和迈克的约定
So this isn't about me breaking my deal with Mike.
而是关于你嫉妒亚历克斯
This is about you being jealous of Alex.
不是  在我发现那是亚历克斯的客户之前
No, it isn't. I thought it was a mistake
我就觉得那是个错误
even before I found out that it was Alex's client.
-哈维  他说的有道理  -扯淡
- Harvey, he has a point. - Bullshit.
你跟我说过  你害怕我和他的关系
You told me you were afraid that I was gonna become
会比我们之间关系更好  就是这么回事
better friends with him than you, and that's what this is.
你竟敢在唐娜面前这样说
How dare you say that to me in front of Donna?
我可是私下告诉你这些的
I told you that in complete confidence.
这不是关于我和亚历克斯的关系
This isn't about my relationship with Alex.
而是关于你和他的关系
This is about your relationship with Alex
以及你不敢直面他
and how you're afraid to stand up to him.
你再跟我说一遍
You want to run that by me again?
我刚跟你说过一遍
I just ran it by you.
你犯了个错误
What you are doing is a mistake.
我不觉得
I don't think so,
唐娜也不觉得  所以说...
and Donna doesn't think so, which means--
实际上  哈维  我也觉得你犯错了
Actually, Harvey, I do.
而且如果你不介意的话  我有话可以自己说
And if it's all the same to you, I can speak for myself.
-你在开玩笑吗  -没有
- Are you kidding me? - No, I'm not.
因为上次你说过  如果我有什么事情要说
Because the last time you said if I had something to say,
就在会上说出来
say it in the goddamn meeting.
而这就是会上了
Well, this is the goddamn meeting.
我觉得应该对迈克信守诺言
And I happen to think we should keep our word to Mike
而不是任凭客户欺辱我们
instead of letting some client bully us.
感谢你的发言
Well, I appreciate the input.
但我说过  需要投票的时候
But I told you you'd get a vote
会有你的一票
when I said there'd be a vote,
而现在不需要投票
and this isn't a vote.
至于你  好好照照镜子吧
As for you, take a look in the mirror,
因为你生气的唯一原因是
because the only reason that you're pissed about this
你的新的好友  为了我取消了和你吃午餐
is your new honeysuckle friend canceled lunch on you for me.
路易
Louis...
你都这么大年纪了  怎么还把假期时间花在
Aren't you a little old to be spending your break
漫画店里
in a comic book store?
每个人都有爱好  迈克
Everybody has their hobbies, Mike.
我的爱好就是漫画
Mine's comics.
而你的爱好就是帮大公司
Yours is helping big corporations
挤兑弱势的一方
screw over the little guy.
等等  奥利佛
Oliver, wait.
我来这里只是想和你道歉
I just, I came here because I owe you an apology,
而这是我道歉的方式
and... this is my way of doing it.
这是什么
What's that?
多花点钱  好摆平事情吗
More money to make everything okay?
这是个案子  它对我来说很重要
It's a case. It's one that means a lot to me.
是关于死于狱中的一个人
It's about a guy who died in prison.
如果这对你那么重要  你干嘛不自己做
If it means so much to you, why don't you do it yourself?
我没法做
I can't.
我们和一个客户有冲突
We have a conflict with one of our clients.
说得很好  迈克  但我还是算了吧
Well, that's a nice speech, Mike, but I'm not interested,
因为还是有你的自身利益在里面  一向如此
because there's something in it for you, like always.
拜托  奥利佛  你拒绝之前
Oliver, please, look, before you say no,
起码听一下我要说的话
just listen to what I have to say.
我不需要再听你说什么了
I don't need to listen to you anymore.
他妈的  我差点死在里面了
God damn it, I almost died in there.
你说什么
What?
我在丹伯里监狱的第二个晚上
My second night in Danbury,
我想那人是来杀我的
I thought that someone was gonna kill me.
然后在我最后一晚
And then my last night,
我知道  同一个人又来了
I knew that same guy was coming for me again.
但我逃了出去
But I got out.
这个孩子没逃出去
This kid didn't.
我在这里唯一的自身利益
The only thing that's in this for me
就是确保这事不会发生在别人身上
is making sure that this doesn't happen to someone else.
这看起来像是早有预谋  迈克
This seems pretty cut-and-dry, Mike.
他们正希望如此
That's how they want it to look.
我已经知道了  他们那天晚上
I already know they didn't have enough guard staff
警卫人手不够
on duty that night.
所以  他们很可能
Which means they probably didn't have
医务人员也不够
enough medical staff either.
说不定根本没有
Or maybe none at all.
听着  我不能任由他们逃脱制裁
Look, I can't let them get away with this
我要把这案子交给那个
without handing it off to the one lawyer
在乎这件事并且能办成的律师
I know cares enough to see it through.
好  迈克
Okay, Mike.
我加入
I'm in.
-唐娜  无论如何  -瑞秋  我真的很抱歉
- Donna, whatever it is-- - Rachel, I'm so sorry.
我犯了个可怕的错误
What I did was wrong and horrible
对你毫无尊重
and showed you no respect,
而当你过来告知我这一点的时候
and then you came and tried to tell me that,
我的做法使它变得更糟了
and I made it a thousand times worse.
那你为什么要那样做
Why would you do something like that in the first place?
因为我也是个新手
'Cause I'm new at this.
我看见斯特芬妮对你那么糟
Then I saw Stephanie treating you like shit,
感觉就像是她在那样对我
and it felt like she was doing that to me.
因为是你给了我这份工作
Because you're the one that gave me the job.
或许吧
Maybe.
然后你说我在拖你的后腿
And then you told me I cut your legs out,
那让我觉得更糟了
and that made me feel even worse,
所以我就拿你泄愤
and I took it out on you.
-唐娜  -瑞秋  你是对的
- Donna-- - Rachel, you were right.
我还没完全准备好
I'm not completely ready for this.
我做的事情并不总是对的
And I'm not always gonna get things right,
而我今天就犯了个大错
and I got them really wrong today.
或许也不是全都错了
Maybe not all wrong.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我自己也想了一下
I thought about it too.
我终于进入律师协会了
I am finally a member of the bar.
我现在谁也不想管
I don't want to supervise anyone right now.
我只想尽自己所能当个好律师
I just want to be the best lawyer I can be.
我明白
I understand.
暂时由我来负责这些律师吧
I'll take care of the associates for now.
唐娜
Donna.
你是怎么想到这些的
What made you realize all that?
这么说吧
Let's just say
有人提醒了我
I was reminded what it feels like
别人代替你说话  而且说的
when someone speaks for you and what they're saying
并不是你想说的意思的感觉
is the complete opposite of what you wanted to say.
-路易吗  -哈维
- Louis? - Harvey.
给你这职位的人
The one who gave you your new position.
没错
Exactly.
我很遗憾  唐娜
I'm so sorry, Donna.
我也是  瑞秋
I'm sorry too, Rachel.
哈维  天很晚了  不管什么事...
Harvey, it's late. Whatever it is--
你是不是把这案子交给诊所了
Did you pawn that thing off to the clinic?
你让我放手  所以我就放手了
You asked me to drop it, so I dropped it.
胡扯
Bullshit.
你把它给了与你有关的诊所
You gave it to the clinic you're affiliated with.
是那个你跟我说允许我任意选择
The clinic you told me I could give cases to
案子给予的诊所
at my discretion.
也许是我没说清楚
Maybe you missed the memo.
如果我们的律所和本案扯上任何关系
If our firm is in any way associated with that case,
我们都会丢失一个大客户
we lose a huge client.
哈维  我已经不办这个案子了
Harvey, I'm not working on it.
那就出一份书面声明
Then you're gonna put that in writing,
而且要交给亚历克斯的客户
and you're gonna deliver it to Alex's client.
铁甲长城
Ironclad Chinese wall.
保证你与本案无关
You have nothing to do with this case.
你的意思是你不信任我吗
Are you saying you don't trust me?
你是在说你把案子交给诊所时
You saying you didn't know what you were doing
不知道这意味着什么吗
when you gave it to the clinic?
好吧  哈维
Okay, Harvey.
我出声明
I'll put it in writing.
我要你亲口给我保证
I want you word you're gonna live
你将遵守声明
by what you sign.
我保证
You have my word.
你找我
You wanted to see me?
是的  我想问问
Yes, I did, I was just wondering,
瑞秋给你的任务你完成了吗
have you redone the assignment that Rachel gave you?
还没有
Not yet.
我的事情一大堆
I had a ton on my plate.
本来打算明天做
I was gonna get to it tomorrow.
你被解雇了
You're fired.
求你  我真的打算做的
Please, I-I really was going to do it.
我相信你
I believe you.
但我的规矩是  三振出局
But my rule is three strikes and you're out.
否则错误总会没完没了
Otherwise, where does it end?
如果这样  为什么不当众宣布
In that case, why not do this publicly?
我不需要当众宣布  斯特芬妮
I don't need to do this publicly, Stephanie.
你明天不来上班了  大家自然明白
When you're not here tomorrow, people will know what happened.
但我想告诉你  我希望你未来会好
But I do want you to know, I wish you well.
你真指望我相信这种话吗
Do you expect me to believe that?
我不知道
I don't know.
但这话是真的
But it's true.
先别急着开口
Before you say anything,
我来是有原因的
I came here for a reason.
因为这里是我们初见的地方
Because this is where we met,
但现在我已经不属于这里
but it isn't where I need to be anymore.
哈维  我不是觉得...
Harvey, I don't think--
我只有一个问题问你
I just have one question to ask you.
你是在担心这个女人的想法
Are you worried about what this woman's gonna think
还是担心我们不合适
or because you think what we're doing is wrong?
因为如果只是担心别人的想法
Because if this is just about what other people think,
那是大错特错
it's crazy.
但我不这么认为
Well, it isn't crazy to me,
而且我需要你理解这一点
and I need you to understand that.
我理解
I do understand that,
但我也知道我们有感情
but I also know we have a connection,
就为了你毫无来由的幻想中的问题
and to throw that away
就把它抛弃...
because of some figment of your imagination--
这不是毫无来由的幻想
It is not a figment of my imagination.
而且我也不是担心她的想法
And I'm not worried about what she thinks.
我担心的是我的想法
I am worried about what I think.
那你的想法是什么
And what is it that you think?
我在想这是不是一个大错误
That what if this was a terrible mistake
如果最后不成呢
and it doesn't work out
如果我在感情里像个傻子呢
and I look like a fool?
好吧
Okay.
我知道你才是心理医生
I know I'm not the therapist here,
但这难道不是每段恋爱都会有的担忧吗
but isn't that the risk of any relationship?
我害怕  哈维
I'm scared, Harvey.
我也是
Me too.
我们一起害怕好吗
What do you say we both be scared together?
有事吗
Can I help you?
有
Yeah.
我叫迈克・罗斯
My name is Mike Ross.
我很想说很高兴见到你
I would say nice to meet you,
但我想你肯定不这么想
but I'm pretty sure you don't feel the same way.
确实
Not particularly.
这是什么
What's this?
我接下来的十五个可能的案子
My next 15 potential lawsuits.
我只是想确保你和这些案子
I just want to make sure you don't have any conflicts
没有什么冲突
with any of these.
也许你客户的奶奶
Maybe your client's grandmother
在12号中提到的超市
shops at the supermarket
购物过
across the street from number 12.
我会看的
I'll take a look.
很好  我想跟你说清楚
Good, 'cause just to be clear,
如果我提前知道有冲突
if I'd known there was a conflict,
我是不会接这个案子的
I never would've taken the case.
谢谢你送来这个
I appreciate you dropping it.
我是被迫送来这个的
I was bulldozed into dropping it,
而且还被迫签了这个
just like I was bulldozed into signing this.
这两件事我可以接受
Now, I can live with both those things,
但我不希望再发生这种状况
but I never want to get caught in this situation again.
笑什么
What's so funny?
我刚跟我的客户说了同样的话
I just told my client the same damn thing.
胡扯
Bullshit.
你以为这件事就让我脸上有光吗
You think this makes me look good?
那看来也许我们真的是一条船上的人
Well then I guess we're in the same boat after all.
很高兴见到你  迈克
It's nice to meet you, Mike.
皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特欢迎你
Welcome to Pearson Specter Litt.
你说我需要面对这种事的策略
You said I needed a strategy for when it happened.
我用了你的策略  放下了这件事
Well, I used your strategy, and I got over it,
但一点问题都没解决
but it didn't fix a goddamn thing!
路易  镇定  有我帮你
Louis, calm down. I'm here for you.
你没有  你从来就没帮过我
No, you're not! You're never there for me.
你永远都要跟我对着干
You're always against me.
我按你的话做了
I did what you said,
但这次  不是我的错
and this time, it's not my fault.
我不管你是怎么想的
And I don't give a shit what you think.
我不是你口中所谓的坏人
I'm not the horrible person you always say I am.
路易  我不觉得你是坏人
Louis, I don't think you're a horrible person.
我觉得你很好
I think you're a wonderful person.
如果我没有让你认识到这一点
And if I haven't made that clear to you,
我真的很抱歉
I am very sorry.
你怎么抱歉都行  哈维
Well, you can be sorry all you want, Harvey.
-路易  -但你看错我了
- Louis? - But you are wrong about me.
我不是没用的废物
I'm not a worthless piece of shit.
是你辜负了我
You failed me.
而且你不该如此
And you were wrong.
你不该
You were wrong!